A Guide to the Additional Charles Wright Papers, 2003-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Charles Wright Papers 2003-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11437-e
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This addition to the Charles Wright Collection was purchased by the University of Virginia Library from Charles Wright, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia, on October 19, 2005.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of additional papers of American poet and University of Virginia English professor, Charles Penzel Wright (1935-), ca. 450 items (3 Hollinger boxes, ca. 1 linear foot) chiefly correspondence, post cards, and greeting cards. Also present is a single poetry notebook containing original hand-written poetry by Wright, 2002-2005, an article, Donald Justice by Mark Strand (2004), and a Times Literary Supplement news clipping mentioning Charles Wright (October 13, 2006).
Most of the correspondence consists of letters, cards, and post cards sent to Charles Wright by fellow poets, fans, and colleagues. These letters have been arranged by the last name of the correspondent. Many of the same correspondents found in the earlier accessions of Charles Wright Papers (#11437, etc.) are also represented in this addition to his papers.
Correspondence about awards, conferences, workshops, poetry readings and other professional engagements, poems submitted to or accepted by poetry magazines and anthologies, requests for permissions to reprint, and requests for Wright to judge poetry contests, write recommendations or evaluate candidates for academic positions are in correspondence folders labeled Requests and Invitations and are arranged chronologically within the folders. Greeting cards and post cards are also arranged chronologically within their folders.
Contents List
- Correspondence: A, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 1:1)
  Correspondents include: Chris Agee; Debra Allbery (includes her poem, All We Need); American Academy of Arts and Letters; Lisa J. Ampleman; Michael Anania; and Dean Edward L. Ayers.
- Correspondence: B, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 1:2)
  Correspondents include: Aaron Baker (includes his poems, Spirits of the Low Ground and Notebook); Lee Bassett (includes his poem, Sirmio); Bruce Beasley; Danny Becker; Marvin Bell; Joelle Biele; Suzette Bishop; Nick Boke; Lucius H. Bracey, Jr.; Jim Brasfield; and Christopher Buckley.
- Correspondence: C, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 1:3)
  Correspondents include: John Casteen (includes his poem, Pausing to Sharpen Tools, I Recall a Line of Russell Annabel); Scott Challener; Jennifer Chang; Danielle Chapman; Mike Chitwood; Jim Churchill; Steve Coyner; and Tony Crunk.
- Correspondence: D-F, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 1:4)
  Correspondents include: Alan DeNiro; Robert D. Denham; William Dutcher; Jonathan Enfield; Peter Everwine; Jeff Fallis; and David Freed.
- Correspondence: G, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 1:5)
  Correspondents include: Joseph Garrison (includes his poem Under the Common Skin); Joseph Giannelli; Elton A. Glaser (includes his poem At the Casino with Justice); and Michael Guista.
- Correspondence: Greeting Cards and Post Cards, 1985, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Correspondence: Greeting Cards and Post Cards, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Correspondence: Greeting Cards and Post Cards, 2004 January-October (Box-folder 1:8)
- Correspondence: Greeting Cards and Post Cards, 2004 November-December (Box-folder 1:9)
- Correspondence: Greeting Cards and Post Cards, 2005 (Box-folder 1:10)
- Correspondence: Greeting Cards and Post Cards, n.d. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Correspondence: H, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 2:2)
  Correspondents include: Connie Hale; Cathryn Hankla; Henry Hart; Kevin Hart; Richard Harteis; Hugh Hennedy; Brian Henry; Gill Holland; Garrett Hongo; and Jeannette Hopkins.
- Correspondence: J, 1987, 2000-2005 (Box-folder 2:3)
  Correspondents include: Paul Jacobs; Leland Jamieson; Mark Jarman; and Donald Justice.
- Correspondence: K, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 2:4)
  Correspondents include: Maxima Kahn; Edmund Keeley; Jack Kehoe; Emma Kimberley; and Karl Kirchway.
- Correspondence: L, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 2:5)
  Correspondents include: Jill Leininger; Phil Levine; Judy Loest; James Longenbach; Rupert Loydell (includes his poem Poetry Letters); and Dave Lucas.
- Correspondence: M, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 2:6)
  Correspondents include: Lynne McMahon; Gerard Malanga (includes his poems Elsa's History, Circa '67 Montale, and canicule); Michelle Margolis; Boyce F. Martin, Jr.; David Martin; John McKernan (his poem Thick Shadows Buried in Dust and Sand;); James McMichael; Sue Ann Mead; Darren J.N. Middleton; Warren L. Molton; Joshua Morison; R.B. Morris; Andrew Mulvania; and Ryan Murphy.
- Correspondence: N-Q, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 2:7)
  Correspondents include: Greg Nix; Philip Pardi; Joseph Parisi; John M. Pelton; Mike Peterson (includes his poem Landscape 8); W.T. Pfefferle; Robert Pinsky; Donald Platt; Nancy and Ed Preston; and Alice Quinn.
- Correspondence: R, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 2:8)
  Correspondents include: Richard Rand; Dave Roeser; Bobby Caudle Rogers, Mark Rosenberg; Lex Runciman; and John Rybicki.
- Correspondence: Requests and Invitations, 2001-2003 April (Box-folder 2:9)
- Correspondence: Requests and Invitations, 2003 July-December (Box-folder 2:10)
- Correspondence: Requests and Invitations, 2004 January-April (Box-folder 3:1)
- Correspondence: Requests and Invitations, 2004 May-December (Box-folder 3:2)
- Correspondence: Requests and Invitations, 2005 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Correspondence: S, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 3:4)
  Correspondents include: David St. John; Mary Ann Samyn; Lynne M. Santos; Francesca Serragnoli; Dave Smith; Katherine Smith; Ellison A. Smyth; Sam Stephenson; and Mary Szybist.
- Correspondence: T, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 3:5)
  Correspondents include: Dorothea Tanning; Eleanor Ross Taylor (1920- ); Phillip Taylor; Sean M. Teaford; John Teschner; Richard Tillinghast; Daniel C. Turner; and Chase Twitchell.
- Correspondence: Mac Test, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 3:6)
- Correspondence: Unidentified and V (Helen Vendler), 2003, 2005, n.d. (Box-folder 3:7)
- Correspondence: W, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 3:8)
  Correspondents include: Rosanna Warren, Randy White; Dara Wier; Lisa Williams; Chris Wiman; Jonah Winter; Shannon Worrell; Franz Wright; and Edith Wylder.
- Correspondence: Y-Z, 2004 (Box-folder 3:9)
  Correspondents include: Margaret Young and Andrew Zawacki.
- Donald Justice by Mark Strand, 2004 (Box-folder 3:10)
- Poetry Notebook, containing original poetry in the hand of Charles Wright, 2002 October 19-2005 September 8 (Box-folder 3:11)
- Poetry Notebook, loose materials removed from the volume and placed in numbered insert files, ca. 2002-2005 (Box-folder 3:12)
- Times Literary Supplement news clipping mentioning Charles Wright, 2006 October 13 (Box-folder 3:13)